(Chinese New Year's Eve,
19th Year of Youning)
(Gu Residence)
(In the 19th Year of Youning,)
(the Gu and Fan families had
been locked in a bitter feud for years.)
(At last, the outcome was decided.)
(The Gu family fell,)
(and their entire clan was executed.)
(Prince Xin, Xiao Changqing,
personally oversaw the execution.)
(Xiao Changqing, Fifth Prince, Prince Xin)
(Thus securing the imperial decree)
(Gu Qingzhi, Prince Xin's Consort)
(to preserve my title as Prince Xin's Consort.)
(Eldest Daughter of the Gu Family)
(I became the only survivor.)
(But how)
(could I go on living
alone in this world?)
(This cup of poisoned liquor)
(is the ending I prepared for myself,)
(and my final move.)
(The Fan family
poisoned Prince Xin's Consort,)
(and cannot escape punishment.)
(I offered my life as bait)
(to make the Fan family
pay for the Gu family's deaths.)
Qingqing.
Qingqing!
Send for the Imperial Physician!
(Where am I?)
(What is this place?)
(Is it a dream,)
(or an illusion?)
(Shen Xihe,
Commandery Princess Zhaoning)
(I never expected)
(that after only three days,)
(I would no longer
see the northwestern landscape.)
Are you homesick, Your Highness?
Ling Long.
I really don't want to go
to the imperial capital.
I want to spend my whole life
in the northwest,
by my father and brothers' side.
Don't say that, Your Highness.
The Duke commands 100,000
frontier cavalry in the northwest.
His military achievements
are illustrious.
His Majesty bestowed upon you
a title of Commandery Princess Zhaoning
with a fief of 3,000 households.
This summons to the palace for
Empress Dowager's birthday banquet
is to arrange your marriage.
I've heard the princes
who are of marriageable age
are all both accomplished
and exceptionally handsome.
You little rascal.
I've spoiled you far too much.
You've become quite unruly.
You should head back first.
I'll stay a little longer.
Yes, Your Highness.
=Blossoms of Power=
(Adapted from the novel, After My
Bloom, All Flowers Wither by Jin Huang)
=Episode 1=
Fatty!
Give us back the Immortal Vine!
Yours?
These hills for miles
around belong to us.
Since the Immortal Vine grows here,
it belongs to us.
- That's right!
- Yes!
The Immortal Vine
grows on a sheer cliff.
You couldn't get it yourself,
(Tian Yuan, Attendant to Crown Prince)
so we picked it first.
Now you're jealous and stole it from us.
So what are you going to do about it?
Not to mention you can't take on
all of us by yourself.
Just look at your master.
He's so frail.
So you great heroes
think you can bully me
because I look weak?
We're bullying you sickly weakling!
Brothers!
- Here!
- Yes!
Get him!
A little exercise will do me good.
Once we return to the imperial capital,
I won't have many chances
to have this much fun again.
(Xiao Huayong, Crown Prince,
Seventh Prince)
Where is he?
Up there!
Get him down!
There he is!
Oh, no!
The Immortal Vine fell into the water!
(Commandery Princess Zhaoning?)
Help me...
Your Highness!
Keep the Immortal Vine for me.
It saved your life.
And I'll come back for it someday.
Your Highness.
Please wake up, Your Highness.
Her Highness is awake.
Your Highness's pulse is steady.
She's out of danger now.
Your Highness...
(Commandery princess?)
(Who are they?)
(Why are they calling me
"Your Highness"?)
Bring me a mirror.
Your Highness.
This is all my fault.
I failed to take proper care of you.
Your Highness.
This is my younger daughter, Zhen Zhu.
Once she's grown,
she will serve Your Highness.
Zhen Zhu?
(Zhen Zhu, Personal Maid
to the Commandery Princess)
(Mo Yu, Personal Maid
Your Highness.
This is Mo Yu.
She has practiced martial arts since
childhood and knows about medicine.
From now on,
she will serve as your personal guard.
Mo Yu?
I'm here, Your Highness.
Where is this place?
Your Highness,
this is
the Lingxiang County Post Station.
Why am I here?
You came to the imperial capital
to attend the Grand Empress Dowager's
birthday banquet
and be matched
in marriage with a prince.
Fortunately, you're safe.
Otherwise, the Duke of Wei's Manor
would have no way
to answer to the court.
The Duke of Wei's Manor?
Is Gu Zhao still the Grand Chancellor?
Back then, the Gu and Fan families
became embroiled
in a political struggle.
The Gu family was wiped out.
But later, the Fan family
also met the same fate
for plotting
to murder Prince Xin's Consort.
(Prince Xin finally understood)
(the true purpose
of that cup of poisoned liquor.)
Who else came with us?
Mo Yuan.
Also, Huang Zhongsi, the fifth-rank
palace attendant sent
by His Majesty to escort Your Highness.
And Ling Long.
After Your Highness fell into the water,
Ling Long jumped in to save you.
She still hasn't been found.
What a loyal maid.
She's the one
who pushed me into the water.
Anyone who didn't know the truth
would think
she risked her life to save me.
Report it to the authorities.
Capture the runaway maid.
Alive if possible.
Dead is acceptable, too.
- Yes, Your Highness.
Your Highness,
it's time for your medicine.
Physician Xie said
this medicine can suppress
the strange poison in your body,
but it also harms your liver and spleen.
Although the Immortal Vine
can't completely cure the poison,
it can strengthen your vital organs.
You risked your life to pick it.
Why did you give it away so easily?
(Without a moment's hesitation,)
(that person used
the rare Immortal Vine to save me.)
The appearance of twin moons
is a sign that
the Star Gate has appeared.
When twin moons hang in the sky,
the Star Gate opens.
Fate is rewritten,
and the world is forever changed.
Since when did Your Highness
learn the art of incense making?
I have no idea.
Since Heaven has given me this chance,
this time,
I will break free of these
vermilion walls and golden roofs.
I will be the one who commands
the board from above,
not a fallen flower
left for others to pluck.
Your Highness,
Huang Zhongsi has caused trouble again.
What happened?
That eunuch abducted
a respectable young lady.
(Huang Zhongsi,)
Greetings,
(Palace Attendant to the Emperor)
Your Highness.
If Your Highness had any orders,
you only had to send for me.
I shouldn't have troubled Your Highness.
I deserve punishment.
Mo Yu.
It's all right.
Come here.
Zhen Zhu.
Give this sachet to Huang Zhongsi.
Yes, Your Highness.
You were ordered to escort me
to the imperial capital,
yet you've committed
such a vile act at the post station.
You violated an innocent young lady.
What punishment do you deserve?
That young lady is a local embroiderer.
She ruined my official robe.
I lost my temper
and slapped her a few times.
She just kept crying and making a scene.
Noisy.
(Mo Yuan, Personal Attendant
to the Commandery Princess)
I serve His Majesty.
Even if I were at fault,
I would answer to His Majesty myself.
Your Highness has no right
to punish me at will.
Otherwise,
you would be disrespecting
the imperial authority.
Your Highness.
I...
I am guilty.
But...
I don't deserve to die.
Don't worry.
This fall won't kill you.
Today,
you'll get a taste
of what it feels like to be forced.
Will you jump,
or should I have someone help you?
Huang... Huang Zhongsi...
He... He was eaten by a wild beast!
The sachet Your Highness
gave Huang Zhongsi...
The Beast Luring Incense.
How did Huang Zhongsi die?
Your... Your Highness,
the eunuch... The eunuch
was escorting Your Highness back
when he fell from his horse
into a ravine.
He was then killed by a wild beast.
Very good.
You're a smart one.
Take him away.
- Thank you, Your Highness.
- Yes.
Your Highness,
once they're back in the imperial
capital, they'll spread rumors.
The more widely they spread, the better.
What does that mean?
Instead of guarding
against them in secret,
I'd rather let them know
I'm not someone to be trifled with.
That way, they won't dare act rashly.
When someone wants
to make you their enemy,
you can't hide forever.
Fear only makes you easy to bully.
Mo Yu.
The former Commandery Princess
was innocent and pure.
She was like a delicate peach blossom
untouched by wind and sand.
But ever since she fell into the water,
she has become
like a flower queen above all others.
If she didn't look exactly the same,
I'd really think she was someone else.
They say Commandery Princess Zhaoning
is gentle and quiet,
frail as a willow in the breeze.
Yet she dared
kill His Majesty's attendant.
How bold of her.
More than bold.
She is ruthless.
Why did you save her
with the Immortal Vine?
At the time,
if I had not given it to her,
she would have died.
You should find a way
to get the Immortal Vine
back as soon as possible.
I already have a plan.
Tagara Incense.
Whose voice
will you take on this time?
Your Highness,
Hua Fuhai, son of Jiangnan's
richest man, requests an audience.
He says he wants the Immortal Vine back.
Hua Fuhai?
I am Hua Fuhai.
I have come today
to ask Your Highness to return
the Immortal Vine.
(That scent is Tagara Incense.)
(I never expected
this man to be a merchant,)
(yet use such deep and noble incense.)
You say the Immortal Vine is yours?
That is right.
The Immortal Vine
is rarely seen in a century.
It was stolen by accident.
After searching everywhere,
I learned it was
in Your Highness' possession.
To be honest,
I accidentally
fell into the river that day.
A righteous man
gave me the Immortal Vine
to save my life.
I cannot hand over
my benefactor's possession
to you based on your word alone.
The Immortal Vine is a rare treasure.
Each plant has a different form.
This one is emerald green throughout
and shaped like a lover's knot.
Have I described it incorrectly?
How about this?
I will set up an unfinished chess game.
If you can solve it,
you win.
Then I will return
the Immortal Vine to you.
What do you say?
One move decides the outcome.
Very well.
Young Master Hua, please solve it.
Your Highness has arranged
such an ingenious puzzle.
Does it have a name?
It is called Moon Palace,
meaning something hazy
and hard to discern.
A fine name.
The puzzle is solved.
Wait.
Young Master Hua, why not look
at the pieces again?
Now,
have you lost?
Interesting.
How did Your Highness
turn the white pieces black?
There is a kind of scented powder
that can color things for a while.
Black can be white,
and white can be black.
Your Highness,
this is clearly deception.
Hardly an honorable victory.
All is fair in war.
In this world,
it is not only a chess piece
whose black and white
are hard to tell apart.
Is that not true?
Well said.
Chess is like a battle.
In the end, all that matters is victory.
I was careless and underestimated you.
I have learned my lesson today.
I accept my loss.
For passing messages,
I still have some means.
They are several times
faster than horses.
I am willing to serve Your Highness.
Thank you, Young Master Hua.
Your Highness,
I think you deliberately left
the Immortal Vine
with the Commandery Princess,
so you would have
a reason to see her again.
Am I right?
Too much talk.
Do not forget.
We came all this way
to wait for Prince Lie.
(Xiao Changying,
Prince Lie, Ninth Prince)
Your Highness.
Prince Lie possesses the Rouge Ledger.
As expected, he's
being hunted by every faction.
The Rouge Ledger
records which officials
committed what crimes,
when and where.
If it falls into someone else's hands,
whether for self-preservation,
to gain favor,
or as leverage,
it could shake the court.
If Your Highness
obtains the Rouge Ledger,
you'll surely find
the clue to the poisoner.
But Prince Lie is risking
his life to protect it.
Along the way,
all his men have been killed.
He's all alone now,
with no chance of winning.
We'll seize the chance to save Changying
and learn where the Rouge Ledger is.
(Prince Lie?)
(Prince Xin's
younger brother, Xiao Changying.)
(Why is he here?)
Without my order,
no one is to make a move.
Yes, Your Highness.
Let's go.
(Ying)
Your Highness, that's Prince Lie.
If we knowingly
leave a prince to be hunted down,
it'll be a crime
that dooms our entire clan.
Save him.
Your Highness.
It looks like Prince Lie
will be rescued
by Commandery Princess.
No "looks like."
I have eyes.
Then,
I'll bring him back later?
Commandery Princess Zhaoning's
marriage alliance
is a matter of great importance.
We must not make a big move.
Tian Yuan.
We leave at once.
Follow Prince Lie's trail
and search for clues.
Yes, Your Highness.
You finally decided to help me.
I failed to recognize Your Highness.
Fortunately,
Your Highness is still alive.
Still alive?
Were you waiting for me to die first?
I've long heard
that Prince Lie's
martial arts are unmatched.
If I hadn't thrown that jade pendant,
would you have stood by
and done nothing?
Please forgive me, Your Highness.
I didn't know the full story.
I couldn't interfere lightly.
After all,
the pursuers aren't always villains.
They may have had no choice.
Nor is the one being hunted
necessarily innocent.
Perhaps he brought it upon himself.
I've never met a lady like you.
What a
beautiful face...
but a venomous heart...
Your Highness.
Prince Lie isn't wearing any clothes.
At a time like this,
you're still worried about propriety?
This is Mandrake Incense.
It will temporarily put him to sleep.
Let's begin.
Your Highness. His Highness
seems to be waking up.
The Mandrake Incense
won't last much longer.
We have to hurry.
Hold down his legs.
Keep going.
Why is Prince Lie holding so hard?
Why are you looking at me like that?
You arranged
for me to cross paths with Prince Lie.
I had no intention of saving him.
Yet you kept urging me to do it.
What do you mean?
Father had long wanted Prince Lie
as his son-in-law, hadn't he?
Speak.
Prince Lie and Prince Xin
are full brothers.
Ever since Prince Xin cut ties
with the Gu family,
he has earned great favor
and become one
of the most prominent princes.
If Your Highness marries Prince Lie,
you'll never again be drawn into
the schemes of the inner palace.
Under Prince Xin's protection,
you'll live a life of peace.
This was the Duke's careful plan.
Father truly meant well.
But do you know where you went wrong?
I...
You were wrong to think
you knew what was best for me.
What I need
is someone obedient and sensible,
someone I can trust with my life,
not a servant who thinks
she's helping by acting on her own.
Now that I've left the northwest,
I'm no longer the little girl
who needed Father and my brothers
to make every decision for me.
I'm about to enter the imperial capital.
I can no longer
remain naive and sentimental.
My affairs, are for no one
but me to decide.
Your Highness,
I know I was wrong.
Please punish me, Your Highness.
The imperial capital
is full of tangled schemes
and hidden dangers.
You and I must stand together
if we're to accomplish anything.
Your Highness,
from this day on,
I will never disobey you
or neglect my duty.
Your Highness.
I found a rare Jade Frost Flower
on Prince Lie's horse.
It doesn't grow
along Prince Lie's usual route.
Just as Your Highness predicted,
we found a patch of Jade Frost Flower.
And this patch of soil
was clearly dug up
and covered over again.
And then?
Then...
we were one step too late.
Who was it
that beat us to it?
Commandery Princess Zhaoning.
Just as Your Highness expected.
I headed southwest
and found the Jade Frost Flower.
I also found this.
(This is a Jade Frost Flower.)
The former Vice Minister of Personnel
had a favored concubine
named Yan Zhi.
She persuaded the Vice Minister
to sell official posts.
But Lady Yan Zhi had another scheme.
More than a decade ago,
she recruited beautiful ladies.
(The Rouge Ledger)
They were married off as concubines into powerful households.
They quietly influenced their husbands
and corrupted the court.
This Rouge Ledger
records the crimes of court officials.
This scent
isn't Prince Lie's fragrance.
It's Jati Blossom Incense.
Rich and refined,
it's a premium Buddhist incense.
Her again?
She beat you to it again.
That little fox with two faces
is becoming more and more intriguing.
No matter which prince
His Majesty chooses for Your Highness,
if you present this to him,
it will be a tremendous help.
He'll surely
be grateful to Your Highness.
Except for the Crown Prince.
Why?
The Crown Prince
has been frail since childhood.
He was poisoned at the age of nine.
At fifteen, he left the capital
for Luotian Temple to recover.
He has no influence at court.
He's a Crown Prince in name only.
All the princes are waiting
for the Crown Prince to die
so they can compete for the throne.
Your Highness, I still think
you should quickly take
the Rouge Ledger back from her.
The Rouge Ledger
will be mine sooner or later.
Let's first see
how my brothers make their moves.
A short life
wouldn't be even better?
Your Highness.
Watch your words.
Even ordinary couples have disputes.
All the more so in a royal marriage.
Rather than scheme and gamble on love,
I'd rather find someone short-lived
and have fewer entanglements.
I've decided
to travel with her
to the imperial capital.
Don't be nervous.
As for who I choose as my husband,
I'll have to meet them all
before I decide.
(The husband best suited for me)
(is not a patron, but an ally.)
(I don't need deep romance.)
(I only need mutual benefit)
(and mutual support.)
(Second. Fifth. Sixth.
Ninth. Crown Prince)
Everyone!
This round, bet on
which prince
Commandery Princess Zhaoning will marry.
The Second Prince, Prince Ning,
devotes himself to law
and has a fine reputation.
I bet on the Second Prince.
(Xiao Changmin, Second Prince,
Prince Ning)
But the Sixth Prince,
Prince Yu, is handsome and striking,
with an exotic charm.
I think the commandery princess
will be charmed by
Daxing's most handsome man.
(Xiao Changyu, Sixth Prince, Prince Yu)
The Fifth Prince, Prince Xin,
kept mourning
(Place of His Late Wife, Lady Gu)
for his late wife for three years.
His Majesty feels sorry for his son,
so he will naturally consider him first.
That makes sense.
Our Ninth Prince, Prince Lie,
is a young general,
brave and battle-hardened.
The commandery princess is the daughter
of the Northwest General.
They would be a perfect match.
I bet on the Second Prince.
I bet on the Sixth Prince.
I bet on the Fifth Prince.
The Sixth Prince.
Bet on the Sixth Prince.
The Ninth Prince.
Why is he betting on the Crown Prince?
You made me owe you my life.
Now you're putting on
an act of playing hard to get?
I am Cui Jinbai, Vice Minister
of the Court of Judicial Review.
Greetings, Your Highness.
If someone impersonates
a court official,
what crime should that be?
This incense is poisonous.
You're faking it.
♪I've hidden so many words♪
♪Too reluctant to tell you♪
♪So never uncover♪
♪The sand that slips away
with one grasp♪
♪The flower that withers
after one bloom♪
♪Silently buried deep inside my heart♪
♪Every answer I gave♪
♪Was both bittersweet and absurd♪
♪Hiding my tear-filled eyes
when I hurt you♪
♪How hard it truly was?♪
♪The wounds that healed
with just a little comfort♪
♪The lies made whole
with a single embrace♪
♪Pretending to be brave
as if I'd never been hurt♪
♪It's a shame I never could♪
♪Give you a moon in return♪
♪With the same open heart you loved me♪
♪I've crossed the wasteland of memories♪
♪Never knowing I was lost♪
♪Why don't you take me away?♪
♪Lead me out of this endless game
of hide-and-seek♪
♪You'll never♪
♪Know how much I long to, long to♪